<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>mapping on Jose Guzman Data Blog</title>
    <link>/categories/mapping/</link>
    <description>Recent content in mapping on Jose Guzman Data Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/mapping/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Animating Mass Shootings in the US from 1982 to 2019</title>
      <link>/post/animating-mass-shootings-in-the-us-from-1982-to-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/animating-mass-shootings-in-the-us-from-1982-to-2019/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The news organization Mother Jones has an open-source database of US mass shootings from 1982 to 2019 available online. The data was gathered as part of an in-depth investigation on mass shootings after the movie-theater shooting in Aurora, Colorado in July, 2012, where 12 people were killed, and over 70 people injured. I’ve been wanting to learn how to animate data visualizations with the gganimate package. I thought that it would be a good idea to animate the mass shooting data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mapping Hurricane Harvey Two Years Later</title>
      <link>/post/mapping-harvey-two-years-later-fema-applications-and-usgs-high-water-marks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/mapping-harvey-two-years-later-fema-applications-and-usgs-high-water-marks/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Two years have passed since Huricane Harvey hit the Texas coastline and Houston area. Harvey stalled for days, pouring rain, overflowing rivers and reserviors, flooding thosands of homes. The hurricane caused more than $125 billion in damage, tying with Huricane Katrina as the costliest storm in U.S. history. In Harris County alone Hurricane Harvey damaged 204,000 homes and apartment buildings. Many Texans still recall how they, their families, or friends lost their homes, their cars, or businesses to the storm.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>