<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Visualization on Jose Guzman Data Blog</title>
    <link>/tags/data-visualization/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data Visualization on Jose Guzman Data Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/data-visualization/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Mapping Harvey Two Years Later: FEMA applications and USGS High Water Marks</title>
      <link>/post/mapping-harvey-two-years-later-fema-applications-and-usgs-high-water-marks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/mapping-harvey-two-years-later-fema-applications-and-usgs-high-water-marks/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Two years have passed since Huricane Harvey hit the Texas coastline and the Greater Houston metropolitan area. Harvey stalled around the Houston area for days, pourring rain, overflowing rivers, and flooding homes. The hurricane caused more than $125 billion in damage, tying with Huricane Katrina as the costliest storm in U.S. history. In Harris County alone Hurricane Harvey damaged 204,000 homes and apartment buildings. Many Texans still recall how they, their families, or friends lost their homes, their cars, or businesses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How (I Think) They Made It: New York Times Game of Thrones Line Graph</title>
      <link>/post/how-i-think-they-made-it-new-york-times-game-of-thrones-line-graph/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/how-i-think-they-made-it-new-york-times-game-of-thrones-line-graph/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The NY Times published an article showing a line graph of IMBd average fan ratings of “Game of Thrones” (“GOT”) episodes over the seasons (as well as line graphs of other popular Tv shows). The authors Josh Katz and K.K. Rebbeca Lai faceted the graph by season, and also added labels with the names of some the episodes with the highest ratings, and one episode from the last season, “The Last of the Starks”, with the all-time low 5.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>