<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jose Guzman Data Blog</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Jose Guzman Data Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Mapping Hurricane Harvey Two Years Later</title>
      <link>/post/mapping-harvey-two-years-later-fema-applications-and-usgs-high-water-marks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/mapping-harvey-two-years-later-fema-applications-and-usgs-high-water-marks/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Two years have passed since Huricane Harvey hit the Texas coastline and Houston area. Harvey stalled for days, pouring rain, overflowing rivers and reserviors, flooding thosands of homes. The hurricane caused more than $125 billion in damage, tying with Huricane Katrina as the costliest storm in U.S. history. In Harris County alone Hurricane Harvey damaged 204,000 homes and apartment buildings. Many Texans still recall how they, their families, or friends lost their homes, their cars, or businesses to the storm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How (I Think) They Made It: New York Times Game of Thrones Line Graph</title>
      <link>/post/how-i-think-they-made-it-new-york-times-game-of-thrones-line-graph/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/how-i-think-they-made-it-new-york-times-game-of-thrones-line-graph/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The NY Times published an article showing a line graph of IMBd average fan ratings of “Game of Thrones” (“GOT”) episodes over the seasons (as well as line graphs of other popular Tv shows). The authors Josh Katz and K.K. Rebbeca Lai faceted the graph by season, and also added labels with the names of some the episodes with the highest ratings, and one episode from the last season, “The Last of the Starks”, with the all-time low 5.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/page/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Aug 2018 02:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/page/about/</guid>
      <description>About Hello, I&amp;rsquo;m Jose Ignacio Guzman. This blog showcases my progress with the R programming language, development of other programming/technical skills, and general ideas about geography, technology, and politics.
My academic background is in international affairs. I began learning the R programming language in early 2018 and haven&amp;rsquo;t stopped since. I&amp;rsquo;m mainly interested in GIS, Cartography, data visualization, and data analysis.My hope with this blog is that it will serve as an archive of things I learn, a guide for answering questions, and hopefully a place to teach others along the way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>/page/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/page/contact/</guid>
      <description>Contact You can contact me a jignacioguz@gmail.com</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>